While giant sharks are more common sea monsters in films, jellyfish also pose a major threat in real life – with some able to kill people with their stings.
虽然巨型鲨鱼是电影里更常见的海洋怪物，但水母在现实生活中也会构成重大威胁——部分水母的刺蜇甚至能致人死亡。
And the potential danger they cause doesn’t stop there, with reports of them attacking salmon farms, shutting down power stations and incapacitating warships.
而且它们造成的潜在危险还不止于此，有报道称水母会袭击三文鱼养殖场、导致发电站停运，还能让军舰失去行动能力。
There are even some scientists in Australia researching whether box jellyfish could ultimately destroy our oceans – so could devouring them be a possible solution?
澳大利亚甚至有科学家在研究，箱型水母是否最终会破坏我们的海洋生态——那么，吃掉它们会不会是一个可行的解决方案呢？
The huge number of jellyfish in our oceans means that if we did start eating them, there is already a large supply of these potential morsels to be dined on.
海洋中水母的数量十分庞大，这意味着如果我们真的开始食用水母，这种潜在食材的供应量已经十分充足。
Also, some people argue that due to their reproductive cycle, jellyfish are actually a sustainable food source.
此外，有人认为，基于水母的繁殖周期，它们其实是一种可持续的食物来源。
Removing a jellyfish from the ocean doesn’t stop new ones being born.
从海洋中捕捞水母，并不会阻止新的水母诞生。
This is because they are spawned from polyps on the seabed.
这是因为水母是由海床上的珊瑚虫繁殖而来的。
In some ways, you can compare them to apples. When you take an apple from a tree, the tree still goes on to produce more apples.
在某种程度上，你可以把它们比作苹果——从树上摘下一个苹果，树依然会结出更多苹果。
What about their nutritional value?
那么水母的营养价值如何呢？
Jellyfish contain 36 calories per ounce, which puts it on a par with iceberg lettuce.
每盎司水母仅含36卡路里热量，这与卷心莴苣的热量相当。
However, unlike lettuce, it is full of protein, making it potentially a great diet food.
但和莴苣不同的是，水母富含蛋白质，因此有可能成为极佳的减肥食品。
And indeed, in many parts of the world, particularly in Asia, they are already consumed, often raw, fried or chopped up as part of a salad.
事实上，在全球许多地区，尤其是亚洲，人们早已开始食用水母，通常会生吃、油炸，或是切碎后加入沙拉中。
The demand for these animals, combined with their numbers, means that selling jellyfish is becoming an ever more lucrative business.
市场对水母的需求，再加上其庞大的数量，意味着售卖水母正成为一门愈发赚钱的生意。
But what do they taste like?
但水母吃起来是什么味道呢？
While some say they are flavourless, others describe them as having a salty taste.
有人说它们没什么味道，也有人觉得带有咸味。
This could be due to their absorbent nature, which also leads them to being often served in a sauce.
这可能是因为水母具有很强的吸附性，这也是它们通常会搭配酱汁食用的原因。
As for the texture, some people negatively compare the experience to eating gristle.
至于口感，有些人会不太满意地将其比作嚼软骨。
So, the next time you fancy chowing down on some fish, you might look at jellyfish as a sustainable alternative.
所以下次你想吃点水产的时候，不妨考虑将水母作为一种可持续的替代品。
They might not be the tastiest thing you’ve ever eaten, but it beats fleeing the sea to avoid being stung.
它们或许不是你吃过的最美味的食物，但总好过为了躲避刺蜇而逃离海洋。